<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Bios on Beyond Words Speech-Language Consultants</title>
    <link>https://beyond-words.github.io/bio/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Bios on Beyond Words Speech-Language Consultants</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Copyright (c) 2017 Beyond Words Speech-Language Consultants</copyright>
    <atom:link href="https://beyond-words.github.io/bio/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Cari Thiele</title>
      <link>https://beyond-words.github.io/bio/cari/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beyond-words.github.io/bio/cari/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Cari has experience with clients preschool-aged through adult.  She has a keen interest in phonological delays, apraxia (motor speech disorders), in fluency (stuttering), early literacy, language development, and accent modification.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Cari loves being a speech-language pathologist because of the relationships that are built with clients and families, and the enjoyment that comes from helping individuals communicate more effectively.  Helping clients meet their speech-language goals is always rewarding!
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Cari has a Bachelor of Education from the University of Regina, and a Master of Science in Speech-Language Pathology from the University of Alberta.  She is registered with the Saskatchewan Association of Speech-Language Pathologists and Audiologists (SASLPA), and is certified with Speech-Language and Audiology Canada.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Cari is a certified provider of:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Lidcombe program for preschool fluency intervention&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hanen, It Takes Two to Talk, a program to teach parents optimal strategies for fostering language development.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Maegan Mason</title>
      <link>https://beyond-words.github.io/bio/maegan/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beyond-words.github.io/bio/maegan/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Maegan completed her Bachelor of Arts degree at the University of Regina and her Masters of Science degree in Speech-Language Pathology at Minot State University. Maegan has developed her career though various opportunities in both the Health and Education sectors. As a result, Maegan possesses a diverse clinical background and enjoys working with individuals of all ages. Maegan lives in Regina with her husband and two children.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Maegan has experience working with adults in the areas of swallowing disorders (i.e., “dysphagia”), communication rehabilitation, tracheostomy/ventilator needs, and accent modification. Maegan also has experience working with children and adolescents in the areas of speech sound production, language, and cognitive impairment. Additionally, Maegan has proficiency in many Assistive and Augmentative Communication (AAC) systems from working with clients of different ages and AAC needs. Lastly, from her time spent as an Autism Consultant, Maegan has an extensive training history and personal interest in the area of Austism Spectrum Disoders and behavioural consultation.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Maegan is a certified group facilitator for Hanen: It Takes Two to Talk and Hanen: Learning Language and Loving It programs. Maegan is also a certified provider of the Compton Pronouncing English as a Subsequent Language accent modification program.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Miranda Miller</title>
      <link>https://beyond-words.github.io/bio/miranda/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beyond-words.github.io/bio/miranda/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Miranda Miller is a licensed Speech-Language Pathologist with experience working with children, youth, and adults with a variety of (dis)abilities.  She obtained her undergraduate (BA) in Psychology with a minor in Linguistics at University of Regina and completed her masters in Speech Language Pathology at Minot State University.  Additionally, Miranda is Hanen certified and trained in the Lidcombe Fluency Program.  Miranda has provided training sessions and presentations and has worked in health and education settings.  Miranda believes in the importance of using evidence based practice and has a keen interest in working with early language development, brain injury, and children who stutter.  She enjoys working with families and team members to create the best possible outcomes.  Miranda lives in Regina with her husband, son, silly french bulldog and moody cat.
 &lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;br /&gt;
(&lt;em&gt;Note: Miranda is not currently accepting clients&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Winter Bengert Siman</title>
      <link>https://beyond-words.github.io/bio/winter/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beyond-words.github.io/bio/winter/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Communication has always been an area of interest for Winter. Members of her family, and she herself have benefited from the expertise of speech language pathologists at different points during their lives. Winter is a graduate of both the University of Regina and Minot State University with a Bachelor&amp;rsquo;s degree in Education and a Master’s degree in Speech Language Pathology. Winter works primarily with toddlers, pre-school children, and school age children experiencing difficulty communicating. She works with clients and their families in various settings including client’s homes, schools, and clinic settings.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Winter is a certified group facilitator for Hanen: It Takes Two to Talk and Hanen: Learning Language and Loving It programs. These programs and the associated strategies used during individual therapy sessions are designed to give parents strategies and confidence to support their child as he/she learns to communicate during everyday interactions.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Winter provides speech and language services in a variety of areas including:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Articulation and speech sound impairments&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Receptive language impairments (the ability to understand the messages of others)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Expressive language impairments (the ability to use language to effectively communicate with others)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Phonological awareness (a pre-requisite skill for the acquisition of reading)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fluency/stuttering&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>